Guide to the Andrew Wellington Cordier Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V:The United Nations Period And Related Files
  - Subseries V.3: United Nations Administration
    - Sub-subseries V.3.1: Administrative Matters
      - UN Service Medal (Box 86)
      - UN World (Box 86)
      - Women United for the UN (info. service) (Box 86)
    - Sub-subseries V.3.2: Dag Hammarskjold Library
      - Bo Beskow(re mural) (Box 87)
      - Bid proposals from construction companies (Box 87)
      - Branch libraries Consultants (Box 87)
      - Demolition contract (Box 87)
      - Documents (Box 88)
      - Ford Foundation (correspondence) (Box 88)
      - Ford Foundation (Century Club luncheon November 1959) (Box 88)
      - Ford Foundation appeal aides memoire and annexes (Box 88)
      - Fuller Company n. 11/1977 (Box 88)
      - General Assembly, 14th session 1959 acceptance of Ford Foundation gift (2 copies) (Box 89)
      - Dag Hammarskjold --suggestions for bust or plaque -The Dag Hammarskjold Library, presentation volume (Box 89)
      - Hangar area (Box 89)
      - Harrison and Abramowitz, architect's contract (Box 90)
      - Harrison and Abramowitz, meetings (Box 90)
      - Interim arrangements (Box 90)
      - Library, proposed new building, 1951-1954 (Box 90)
      - Perry Marthin (sp?) colour consultant (Box 90)
      - Miscellaneous file (correspondence, memos) (Box 90)
      - New York City, Correspondence (Box 90)
      - Photograph of architect's rendering by Ferris (Box 90)
      - Press releases (Box 90)
      - Slattery Construction Co. (Box 90)
      - Tributes from staff to Mr. Cordier (Box 90)
      - Vaughan progress reports (Box 90)
      - Vaughan working memoranda (Box 90)
      - Dedication and Symposium 16-18 November 1961 (Box 91)
        - Administrative arrangements (Box 91)
        - Cables sent -- confirmation copies (Box 91)
        - Chronological file --letters and cables sent (Box 91)
        - Journal announcement (Box 91)
        - Library of Congress Information Bulletin (Box 91)
        - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 91)
        - Programme (Box 91)
        - Press and photos (Box 91)
        - Symposium. drafts and final texts (Box 91)
        - Travel of participants (Box 91)
        - Social events: (Box 92)
          - Invitations (Box 92)
          - U Thant luncheon November 16, 1961 (Box 92)
          - Dedication Ceremony, November 16, 196l (Box 92)
          - U Thant reception November 16, 1961 (Box 92)
          - U Thant luncheon November 17, 1961 (Box 92)
          - U Thant reception November 17, 1961 (Box 92)
          - Buffet, November 18, 1961 (Box 92)
          - Reception for Bo Deskow, November 27, 1961 (Box 92)
        - Invitation section:
          - Ford Foundation (Box 92)
          - Woodrow Wilson Foundation (Box 92)
          - Special guests, (6 Folders) (Box 92)
          - Individuals (separate files), (9 Folders) (Box 92)
          - Librarians (from Member States)--separate files, (44 Folders) (Box 93)
          - Consultants and Institutes, (5 Folders) (Box 93)
    - Sub-subseries V.3.3: Personnel
      - Staff Day 1953 (first staff day) (Box 94)
      - Staff Day 1954 (Box 94)
      - Staff Day 1961 (last with Mr. Hammarskjold) (Box 94)
      - Applicants—correspondence:
        - Alphabetical files, A-Z (Box 94)
      - Staff Members -- correspondence (Box 95-97)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Alphabetical files, A-Z (Box 95-97)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Individual files by .name:
          - Bokhart (Box 95-97)
          - Bunche (Box 95-97)
          - Feller (Box 95-97)
          - Flynn (Box 95-97)
          - Foote (Box 95-97)
          - Hill (Box 95-97)
          - Hillis (Box 95-97)
          - Katzin (Box 95-97)
          - Lall, S. (Box 95-97)
          - Laugier (Box 95-97)
          - Mills (Box 95-97)
          - Power (Box 95-97)
          - Samper (Box 95-97)
          - Smith, G.I. (Box 95-97)
          - Vigier (Box 95-97)
          - Von Horn (Box 95-97)
          - Wieschoff (Box 95-97)
      - Documents (Box 98)
      - Reports of the Secretaries-General to the General Assembly on the Staff of the UN Secretariat:
        - 21 October 1947 A/C5/W2l Second session (Box 98)
        - 27 February 1949 Fourth session (Box 98)
        - 25 Sep. 1950 A/C5/L. 48 Fifth session (Box 98)
        - 31 October 1951 A/C5/L.108 and Rev. 1 Sixth session (Box 98)
        - 7 October 1952 A/C5/L 176 Seventh session (Box 98)
        - 16 September 1953 A/C5/L. 234 Eighth session (Box 98)
        - 20 Sep. 1954 (ST/ADM/R.7) Ninth session (Box 99)
        - 23 Sep. 1955 A/C5/L.l31 Tenth session (Box 99)
        - 28 Sep. 1956 A/C5/L.39l and Corr. 1 Eleventh session (Box 99)
        - 12 Sep. 1957 A/C5/L.456 Twelfth session (Box 99)
        - 17 Sep. 1958 A/C5/L.508 Thirteenth session (Box 99)
        - 17 Sep. 1959 A/C5/L. 564 Fourteenth session (Box 99)
        - 30 Sep. 1960 A/C5/L. 609 and Add. I Fifteenth session (Box 99)
        - 29 Sep. 1961 A/C5/L. 672 Sixteenth session (Box 99)
    - Sub-subseries V.3.4: Organization Of Secretariat
      - Miscellaneous files: (Box 100)
        - Amalgamation of Technical Assistance and Economic and Social Affairs 1957-58 CONF (Box 100)
        - Geographical Distribution, 1961-1962 (USA, USSR) (Box 100)
        - International Administrative Service, creation of (Docs., correspondence 1956-58) (OPEX program) (Box 100)
        - Miscellaneous memos, drafts, 1957-1958 (Box 100)
        - Role of Secretariat in the Work of United Nations Organs (paper by Secretary-General, 1953) Conf. (Box 100)
        - Secretary-General's office; integrated Administration, 1958-1959 (Box 100)
        - Troika, public statements, 1961 government representatives (Box 100)
        - Succession of Secretary-General: interregnum period, Sep-Nov 1961 (Cordier role) (Box 100)
        - World Federation of United Nations Organizations, Geneva 1961 (Pelt letter) (Box 100)
      - Secretary-General's Departmental Review, 1959 (one Folder) (Box 100)
      - Committee of Three -­ Past Presidents General Assembly (organization of the Secretariat at senior level, 1960):
        - Correspondence (Box 100)
        - Report (Box 100)
      - Committee of Experts, 1960-1961 (General Assembly):
        - Geographical distribution (Box 100)
        - Interim Report (Box 100)
        - Minutes (49) (Box 100)
        - Miscellaneous correspondence 1960-1961 (Box 100)
        - Report of Committee, draft (Box 101)
        - Report of Committee, final and SG's comments (Box 101)
        - Working Papers, 1961 (Box 101)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Secretary Committee: drafts, confidential memos and comments (Box 101)
        - Secretary of Committee: working memoranda (Box 101)
        - Secretary-General's correspondence with M. Georges-Picot (Committee member) (Box 101)
      - Public Information:
        - Miscellaneous correspondence & memoranda, 1956-1958 (Box 101)
        - Consultative Panel, 1960 (General Assembly Res. 1405 XIV) (Box 101)
        - General Assembly resolution 1335 XIII 1958--Recommendations of Office of Public Information (Box 101)
        - Expert Committee On Public Information (GA Resolution 1177 (XII), 1957):
          - Lochner correspondence (Box 101)
          - Report to 13th Session General Assembly 1958 (Box 101)
          - Draft resolutions, 13th session (Box 102)
          - Statements of Secretary-General (Box 102)
          - Statements of representatives at 13th session (Box 102)
      - Documentation (miscellaneous) (Organization of Secretariat):
        - Survey Group Reports 1954 and 1955 (Box 102)
        - General Assembly --Reports of Secretary-General and Advisory Committee 1948, 1953 -1955 and 1957 (Box 102)
        - Fifth Committee, miscellaneous documents, 1954-1959 (Box 102)
        - General Assembly documents, 1960 (Box 103)
        - General Assembly documents, 1961 (Box 103)
        - General Assembly and Fifth Committee, 1962 (Box 103)
        - General Assembly, 16th session, 1961 Excerpts from statements in general debate on reorganization of Secretariat (Box 103)
        - General Assembly, 16th session, 1961 Excerpts from statements in general debate on role and structure of the UN (Box 103)
        - Information Circulars, Secretary-General's Bulletins 1954-1960 (Box 103)
    - Sub-subseries V.3.5: US Government --Security Investigations, UN Staff Members
      International Organizations Employees Loyalty Board (copies of letters to the Secretary-General from the US Mission to the UN transmitting reports on individual staff members (names listed in each 1etter) (8 Folders)
      - Volume I, 1953-54 (Box 104##)
      - Volume II, 1954-56 (Box 104##)
      - Volume III, 1956-57 (Box 104#)
      - Volume IV, 1957-58 (Box 104#)
      - Volume, V 1958 (Box 105#)
      - Volume, VI 1959 (Box 105#)
      - Volume, VII 1959-60 (Box 105#)
      - Volume, VIII 1961 (Box 105#)
      - Folders on hearings of individual US staff members:
        - R. J. Bunche (Box 105#)
        - A. Davidson (Box 105#)
        - G. Duran (Box 105#)
        - O. Lattimore (Box 105#)
        - W. Ranallo (Box 105#)
        - E. Wallach (Box 105#)
        - David Weintraud and Irving Kaplan:
          - 2 volumes of hearings before the US Senate Subcommittee on Internal Security (Box 105#)
          - 1 file Folder with memoranda (Box 105#)
      - Non-US Staff Members, security investigations: (Box 106#)
        - General file, several memos (Box 106#)
        - *Gubitchev case (procedures for providing info. to UN Sec. Gen.): (Box 106#)
      - U.S. Executive Order 10422 (procedures for providing info. To UN Sec. Gen.):
        - Folder with listed and numbered papers Jan-Feb 1953 (Box 106#)
        - Folder with papers from Jan-September 1953 (Box 106#)
      - US Senate Investigation of US staff members:
        - Folder #1 (SG and Cordier ): contains 74 numbered working papers 1948-1953 filed in chronological order (Box 106#)
        - Folder #2 (SG and Cordier): contains 36 numbered working papers 1952-1953 filed 1n chronological order (communications of Staff organizations, Specialized Agencies, UN officials, Sg Statements, etc.) (Box 106#)
      - US Federal Bureau of Investigation (memos, 1949) (Box 107#)
      - US Federal Grand Jury: contains 13 numbered working papers 1952-1953 and 3 additional unnumbered papers (Box 107#)
      - US House of Representatives, Foreign Affairs Committee:
        - Report on 8th Session UN (1954) (Box 107#)
        - Study on Int. Organizations (Box 107#)
      - *(RESTRICTED) US House of Representatives Committee on the Judiciary, 1952-1953 (hearings & report) (Box 107#)
      - US House of Representatives Com. on Un-American Activities (hearing 1949) (Box 107#)
      - US Senate, McCarran Bill. 1953 (Box 107#)
      - US Senate, Committee on the Judiciary: (Box 108#)
        - Stenographic Transcripts, (3 Folders) (Box 108#)
        - Hearings, Reports (Box 108#)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Miscellaneous Folder: press releases, articles, statements, etc. (Box 108#)
      - US State Department: (Box 109)
        - Marshall Committee of Inquiry 1948 re UN (text of report, press re1eases,memos) (Box 109)
        - Passport cases, UN staff members, 1951-1953 (Box 109)
      - United Nations panels, committees, etc.:
        - Advisory Panel 1953 (Box 109)
        - Commission of Jurists 1952-1953 contains 32 papers numbered, filed in chron. order plus several unnumbered (Box 109)
        - Walters Committee (memo 7) (Box 109)
        - Member States' comment on personnel policy (Box 109)
    - Sub-subseries V.3.6: Miscellaneous UN Subjects
      - Approaches to Foundations 1950-1961 (Box 110)
        - General file (Box 110)
        - Ford Foundation (Box 110)
      - General Assembly:
        - Interim Committee, memos, notes, 1950 (Box 110)
        - SG meetings with delegations re opening date of 7th session: 15 and 20 May 1952 (Box 110)
      - San Francisco UN Commemorative Conference 1955
        - Correspondence Folder:
          - General file (Box 110)
          - Robert Gros, Chairman, Executive Committee, San Francisco (Box 110)
          - Invitation, City of San Francisco to UN, preliminary correspondence 1954 (Box 110)
          - Trygve Lie, invitation to conference (confidential) (Box 110)
          - Member States (Box 110)
          - Harry Truman (Box 110)
          - San Francisco officials (Box 110)
          - Eelco van Kleffens, President, General Assembly (Box 110)
          - UN arrangements, miscellaneous file (Box 110)
      - Press:
        - Press conferences (Box 110)
        - Press clippings, 2 Folders (Box 110)
      - Commemorative Folder: (Box 111)
        - Proceedings of meetings 20-26 June 1955 (Box 111)
        - Conference Telephone Directory (Box 111)
        - Miscellaneous re entertainment, social events (Box 111)
      - Specialized Agencies:
        - Administrative Committee on Co-ordination 1949-1951 correspondence, memos (Box 111)
        - GATT 1951 (General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade) (Box 111)
        - International Bank, 1957-1960 (Box 111)
        - International Labour Organization, 1949-1951 correspondence, memos. (Box 111)
        - International Monetary Fund (text of agreement between IMF and UN 1948) (Box 111)
        - International Refugee Org'n (text of agreement with UN 1949) (Box 111)
        - International Telecommunications Union (text of agreement with UN 1949) (Box 111)
        - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, correspondence etc. 1948-1954 (Box 111)
        - Universal Postal Union (text of agreement with UN 1949) (Box 111)
        - World Health Organization (correspondence, memos 1949-1950 also text of agreement with UN 1949) (Box 111)
      - United Nations Guard (proposed):
        - Documents, General Assembly Special Committee on a UN Guard 1949 (Box 111)
        - Miscellaneous papers, 1948-1949 (evolution of UN Guard proposal into establishment of UN Field Service 1949) (Box 111)
      - United Nations Police Force (proposed): misc. correspondence, memos, etc. 1949-1958 (Box 111)
      - (UNHCR) United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees/(correspondence, etc. 1950-1960) (Box 111)
      - UNSCCUR (Box 112)
      - United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF): correspondence, info. materials, etc. 1948-19[?] (Box 112)
      - Secretary-General's "Private" meetings (heads of departments or offices 1946-1958) (-1951) 10 Folders: 1946, 1947 *(RESTRICTED) 1948-49, 1950-51, 1952, 1953 1954-55 (Box 112)
      - Secretary-General's "Private" meetings (1952-1956) 1956, 1957, 1958 (agenda, minutes--not all complete) (Box 113)
      - Secretary-General's "Private" meetings *(RESTRICTED) (1957) (Box 114)
      - Top Ranking Directors’ meetings (senior staff)--Mr. Cordier, chairman (1949-1953) (1 Folder) (Box 114)
      - Outside Organizations:
        - Brookings Institution (correspondence & studies), 1950-1960 (Box 114)
        - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (correspondence & studies) 1948-1960 (Box 114)
        - Christian Century (correspondence), 1953-1954 (Box 115)
        - Columbia University: (Box 115)
        - American Assembly (correspondence, studies), 1954-1957 (Box 115)
        - Joint Committee UN and Columbia University (memos), 1954 (Box 115)
        - Council on Foreign Relations (correspondence, memos), 1957-1959 (Box 115)
        - Foreign Policy Association (correspondence), 1954-55 (Box 115)
        - Freedom House (correspondence), 1953-54 (Box 115)
        - Metropolitan Opera, UN Committee (SG correspondence 1951) (Box 115)
        - Moral Re-armament (correspondence), 1951-53 (Box 115)
        - National Council of Churches (correspondence), 1953-1958 (Box 115)
        - New York University:
          - General correspondence, 1953-1958 (Box 115)
          - Arts Centre Association (proposed Centre near UN) -Correspondence 1952-54 (Box 115)
        - University of the State of New York, State Education Dept. (correspondence 1954) (Box 115)
        - World Federation of UN Associations (correspondence) 1956-1959 (Box 115)
  - Subseries V.4: The Secretaries General
    (The following list does not necessarily represent all trips made by Mr. Lie as there was no log of his trips in the Cordier file)
    - Sub Subseries V.4.1: Trygve Lie
      - Trygve Lie trip files: (Box 116)
        - 1947
          - Central America: (Mexico, Guatemala, San Salvador, Teguegalpu, Managua, San Jose, Balboa, Havana, Port au Price, Cuidad Trujillo, San Juan), 10-30 January 1947 (Itinerary, reporting, cables) (Box 116)
          - Oslo, March 1947 (Reporting cables and correspondence) (Box 116)
          - Oslo, 7 June-8 August 1947 (Reporting cables) (Box 116)
        - 1948
          - Geneva, Berne, Paris, Brussels, The Hague, Amsterdam, Prague, Oslo, London (Reporting cables and correspondence} (Box 116)
          - London, Paris, Geneva July 1948 (Reporting cables) (Box 116)
          - Warsaw, 27-29 August 1948 (Cables re. arrangements; it would appear trip was cancelled) (Box 116)
          - Oslo, 1-17 September 1948 (prior to Paris Assembly) (Cables, correspondence memos (death of Bernadotte 17 September) (Box 116)
          - Paris, Sep-December 1948 (UN General Assembly) (No file) (Box 116)
        - 1949
          - Oslo, Copenhagen, Stockholm, July-August 1949 (Reporting cables) (Box 116)
          - 1950 (Box 116)
          - Florida, March-April 1950 (Reporting letters) (Box 116)
          - "Moscow trip": (London, Paris, The Hague, Geneva, Moscow, Paris London), 26 April 23 May 1950 (Reporting cables and letters) (Box 116)
          - Oslo, 12-31 August 1950 (Reporting cables) (Box 116)
          - Oslo, December1950-January1951 (Reporting cables) (Box 116)
        - l95l:
          - Santiago, Lima, Quito, Palm Beach, Feb-Mar 1951 (Reporting cables) (Box 116)
          - Middle East --Athens, Cairo, Lebanon, Ankara, Israel, Apr-May 1951 (Itinerary, reporting cables) (Box 116)
          - Oslo, Copenhagen, June 1951 (Reporting cables, Korea) (Box 116)
          - Oslo, Geneva Paris, re 6th session G/A, Ju1-Aug 1951 (Reporting cables) (Box 116)
          - Paris (6th session of the G/A), 16 Nov-Dec 1951 (No file) (Box 116)
        - 1952 (Box 117)
          - Paris (6th session of the G/A), Jan-Feb 5, 1951 (No file) (Box 117)
          - Oslo, Feb 1952 (Reporting cables) (Box 117)
          - London, Brussels, Paris, Geneva, Vienna, Copenhagen, Oslo, Helsinki, Stockholm, June-August, 1952 (Reporting letters and cables) (Box 117)
          - London,.Paris, Sept 1952 (Reporting cables) (Box 117)
    - Sub-subseries V.4.2:Dag Hammarskjold 1953-1961
      Country log of trips. Blue binder: Not necessarily complete. Chronological log of trips, 1953-1961 (file Folder). Some gaps
      - Following list includes. trips on which no file exists: (Box 117)
        - 1953
          - Stockholm-New York, April 1953 (*No file: to accept post as SC) (Box 117)
          - Washington, 6 May 1953 (*No file) (Box 117)
          - Geneva, Stockholm, London 13 May-9 Jun 1953 (Reporting cables) (Box 117)
          - Ottawa, 25 June 1953 (Itinerary--visit to Pearson as President General Assembly) (Box 117)
          - Geneva, 29 Jul-4 Aug 1953 (Reporting cables; press release) (Box 117)
          - Washington, 11-13 Sep. 1953 (Itinerary; reporting cables) (Box 117)
          - Stockholm, 14-19 Oct 1953 (Reporting cables) (Box 117)
          - London, 15-19 Dec 1953 (1 letter) (Box 117)
        - 1954
          - Cincinnati, 13-14 Jan 1954 (*No file) (Box 117)
          - Toronto, Ottawa 25-27 Feb 1954 (*No file) (Box 117)
          - Caracas, 1-4 Mar 1954 (Cables) (Box 117)
          - Stockholm, London, 10-20 Mar 1954 Itinerary; reporting cables (Box 117)
          - Washington, 31 Mar-l Apr 1954 (No file) (Box 117)
          - Washington, 14 Apr 1954 (*No file) (Box 117)
          - Washington, 26 Apr 1954 (*No file) (Box 117)
          - San Francisco, Los Angeles, Chicago, Minneapolis, 12-18 May 1954 (*No file) (Box 117)
          - Paris, Geneva, 22-28 May 1954 (*No file) (Box 117)
          - Washington, 2 Jun 1954 (*No file) (Box 117)
          - Geneva via Paris, Copenhagen and Malmo (Sweden), 3-20 July 1954 (Reporting cables) (Box 118)
          - *This information taken from chronological log of Hammarskjold trips on AWC files (Box 118)
          - "General review of contents done 1974 for research for book (further) (Box 118)
        - 1954
          - Boston, 6-8 August 1954 (*No file) (Box 118)
          - Chicago, 20-21 August 1954 (*No file) (Box 118)
          - Stockholm, 17-22 December 1954 (*No file) (Box 118)
          - Peking (via London, Paris, Hong Kong), 30 Dec-13 Jan 1955 (Cables) (Box 118)
          - Albany 28 Mar 1955 (*No file) (Box 118)
          - Stockholm, Geneva, London, Paris, 20 Apr -2 May 1955 (Reporting cables (Box 118)
          - Washington 17 May 1955 (*No file) (Box 118)
          - Paris 21-28 May 1955 (*No file) (Box 118)
          - Baltimore 13-14 Jun 1955 (*No file) (Box 118)
          - San Francisco (UN 10th Anniversary commemorative conference, 18-27 Jun 1955 (No trip file) (Box 118)
          - Geneva, Stockholm, Malmo, 9 Jul -11 Aug 1955 (Reporting letters, cables) (Box 118)
          - Bogota 27-30 Aug 1955 (*No file) (Box 118)
        - 1956
          - Middle East, Sub-Continent, S.E. Asia (Athens, Ankara, Cairo, Tel Aviv, Amman, Beirut, Teheran, Damascus, Baghdad, Karachi, New Delhi, Rangoon, Bangkok, Djakarta, Canberra, Wellington), 15 Jan-24 Feb 1956 (*(RESTRICTED) Reporting cables; itinerary) (Box 118)
          - Washington 29 February 1956 (*No file) (Box 118)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Middle East--(Cairo, Gaza, Jerusalem, Beirut, Teheran, Damascus, Baghdad, Karachi, New Delhi, Rangoon, Bangkok, Djakarta, Canberra, Wellington) (Omnipress cables) (Box 118)
          - Washington, 29 February 1956 (*No file) (Box 118)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Middle East--(Cairo, Gaza, Jerusalem, Beirut, Amman, Damascus also Vatican visit in Rome), 6 Apr-6 May 1956 (Reporting cables) (Box 118)
          - Williamsburg, 4-15 May 1956 (*No file) (Box 118)
          - Montreal, 29-31 May 1956 (Itinerary McGill Univ. and International Law Assoc) (Box 118)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Europe, Middle East--(Warsaw, Moscow, Prague, Vienna, Belgrade, Geneva, Jerusalem, Beirut, Cairo), 27 Jun-27 Jul 1956 (4 Folders: 1. Itinerary file; 2Press releases, statements, press conferences; 3. Reporting letters, cables, telex,;4 Correspondence files re trip arrangements) (Box 118)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Middle East-(Abu, Suweir, Cairo), 13-19 November 1956 (Reporting cables) (Box 118)
        - 1957
          - Stockholm, January 1957 (*No file) (Box 119)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Middle East: Cairo, Beirut (via Brussels, Athens, Rome, Paris, 19-28 March 1957 (Reporting cables) (Box 119)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Middle East: Geneva, Jerusalem, 28 April-12 May 1957 (Reporting cables) (Box 119)
          - Boston, 12-13 June 1957 (*No file) (Box 119)
          - Geneva, Malmo (Sweden), 28 June-19 July 1957 (Reporting cables; telex) (Box 119)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Middle East: Beirut, Amman, Jerusalem, Damascus, 29 Non.-7 December 1957 (Reporting cables) (Box 119)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Stockholm; Gaza (for Xmas), Cairo, 18 December-29 December 1957 (Reporting cables; itinerary) (Box 119)
        - 1958
          - London, 15-18 January 1958 (Cables re arrangement reporting cables, press releases) (Box 119)
          - Cleveland, 4-5 February 1958 (Itinerary and schedules) (Box 119)